# Vernon R. King, III

Having felt an earnest call to ministry since college, I have been preparing for church ministry through internship opportunities, academic study, voracious reading, intense dialog, and a foray into electronic publishing while simultaneously pursuing a career in software development. Although my primary focus has been church health, including church planting and church strengthening, I have also been gifted in personal counseling and have experience in adoption ministry.

I affirm the <u>Abstract of Principles</u>,<sup>1</sup> the <u>Baptist Faith and Message 2000</u>, the <u>Chicago Statement on Biblical Inerrancy</u>, and the Danvers Statement on Biblical Manhood and Womanhood.

### **Education**

Southeastern Baptist Theological Seminary | Wake Forest, North Carolina *Master of Divinity in Christian Ministry* 

**GPA: 4.0** 

Texas A&M University | College Station, Texas

Bachelor of Science in Computer Engineering, summa cum laude

GPA: 4.0

### **Relevant Experience**

#### First Baptist Church | Durham, North Carolina

Pastoral Intern January 2014–May 2014

Met weekly with pastors to discuss ministry in a healthy church:

- Attended elders and members meetings
- Read and reported weekly on ecclesiological texts

Pillar on the Rock | Ecclesiological Online Magazine

Co-founder and Editor, www.pillarontherock.com

2009-2011

Wrote 50+ and edited 100+ articles to promote local church health:

- Article reprinted in B&H book, <u>Preach: Theology Meets Practice</u>, by Mark Dever and Greg Gilbert
- Grew the writing team to include six authors

New Song Church | Windhoek, Namibia

Missionary Intern

May 2007-August 2007

Residential intern with an IMB missionary team:

- Assisted in the leadership and administration of a weekly outreach serving 150+ students
- Observed cross-cultural pastoral ministry on a daily basis

<sup>&</sup>lt;sup>1</sup>Excepting XVII. "The Lord's Day."

# Vernon R. King, III

### **Professional History**

Southeastern Baptist Theological Seminary | Wake Forest, North Carolina

Software Developer May 2013–present

FTS International | Fort Worth, Texas

Lead Software Developer May 2011–January 2013

Deloitte Consulting | Dallas, Texas

Software Consultant, Homeland Security January 2011–May 2011

FIS | Oklahoma City, Oklahoma

Senior Programmer Analyst October 2009-November 2010
Programmer Analyst II September 2007-October 2009

### **Personal Background**

Contact

81 McDowell Dr.

Wake Forest, North Carolina 27587

vernon.king@outlook.com | (817) 458-8174

Website: http://www.vernonking.org

Sermons: <a href="http://www.vernonking.org/sermons/">http://www.vernonking.org/sermons/</a>

Blog: http://www.adoptedbytheking.com

Family

Kathryn Rose (spouse), Vernon Ray, IV (11), Brooklyn Leigh (8), Emma Grace (4), Seth

Christopher (1).

Some of our children were adopted in 2011.

#### References

Nathan Finn, Ph.D.

Elder, First Baptist Church, Durham

Associate Professor, Southeastern Seminary

(919) 280-4309

nfinn@sebts.edu

Ryan Hutchinson, M.Div.

Elder, First Baptist Church, Durham

EVP for Operations, Southeastern Seminary

(919) 761-2200

hutchinson@sebts.edu

Benjamin H. Arbour, Ph.D.

Mentor and Friend

(979) 574-1300

benarbour03@yahoo.com

Andy Winn, M.Div.

Associate Pastor, First Baptist Church, Durham

(919) 452-1427

andy.winn@fbcdurham.org

David Jacks

Lead Pastor, Church of Christ the King

(817) 395-2180

davidjacks1967@gmail.com